Pressure can lead you to the bad or the good.
压力可能带来好的或坏的结果
I feel everything: the emotions,
我感受到一切：那些情感
the desire to play football.
对踢球的渴望
I love the atmosphere,
我喜欢这种氛围
the pressure, the fans.
压力，球迷
I understand half of it, but I understand.
我只能理解一半，但我确实理解
My family motivates me.
我的家人激励着我
I am in love with football.
我热爱足球
DEFINITION OF PRESSURE
压力的定义
It's something we feel everyday.
这是我们每天都能感受到的
It ends up being natural.
它最终变得很自然
It's hard to handle it.
应对起来很困难
Pressure: Moral force or influence exerted on a person to condition his or her behavior.
压力：施加在一个人身上的道德力量或影响，以调节其行为。
"Resist social pressures" Similar: coercion, duress, compulsion, constraint, imposition, influence, coercion, commandment
"抵抗社会压力" 相似词：强制、胁迫、约束、限制、强加、影响、强制、命令
I think it's important not to hide the pressure,
我认为重要的不是隐藏压力
but rather to normalize it.
而是要让它变得正常化
The pressure on the field
场上的压力
in the end, it ends up being something natural.
最终会变成很自然的事情
I, personally, have a way of
就我个人而言，我有一种方式
eliminate the pressure unconsciously.
在无意识中消除压力
In the end, it is something we have everyday.
最终，这是我们每天都会遇到的事情
Being players of big clubs,
作为大俱乐部的球员
of a team like the Argentine national team.
作为阿根廷国家队这样的球队的一员
When I enter the field,
当我走上球场时
everything that happens off the field
场外发生的一切
does not interfere with what I am doing.
都不会影响我正在做的事
Pressure can lead you to the bad or the good.
压力可能带来好的或坏的结果
The pressure on someone, pressuring someone,
对某人施加压力
can bring out the best, as it happens to me.
可能激发出最好的一面，就像发生在我身上的那样
It motivates me.
它激励着我
I feel it brings out the best in me.
我感觉它能激发出我最好的一面
Pressure is hard to handle.
压力很难应对
We always try to stay calm,
我们总是试图保持冷静
try not to think too much, about what, about what, we are playing,
试图不去想太多，关于我们正在比赛的事情
although it is also difficult.
尽管这也很困难
So, pressure... I can say
所以，压力...我可以说
that I know how to deal with it very well.
我知道如何很好地应对它
The World Cup was a clear example of that, of how pressure pushed me further.
世界杯就是一个明显的例子，展示了压力如何推动我前进
We had the personality to face it,
我们有勇气去面对
and all that pressure, and that nervousness
所有的压力和紧张
made us stronger as a group and individually.
让我们作为一个团队和个人都变得更强大
Family
家庭
I remember the game against Brazil.
我记得对阵巴西的那场比赛
It was very special because I had many things on my mind.
那场比赛很特别，因为我心里有很多事情
Because, I was going through a situation.
因为，我当时正经历一些
Not a very good one, because of my family, because of what happened with my father.
不是很好的处境，因为我的家人，因为发生在我父亲身上的事
There were many thoughts, many motivations,
有很多想法，很多动力
a lot of desire to go to the field and win.
很想上场去赢得比赛
And it was like that.
结果也确实如此
I scored two goals,
我进了两个球
that I gave to the team and it was a spectacular day.
我为球队打进的两个进球，那是美好的一天
Leaving my family at 12 years old,
12岁时离开家人
and going to Indepediente’s boarding school
去了独立队的寄宿学校
and then, leaving my brother alone in Argentina
然后，把我的兄弟一个人留在阿根廷
going to England at 16, 17 years old.
16、17岁就去了英国
That, actually, is pressure. Being away from your family,
那才是真正的压力，远离家人
not knowing if you will make it and having my family far away, that is bad.
不知道自己是否能成功，而家人又在远方，那很糟糕
The pressure of playing on a field
在球场上比赛的压力
or playing, I don't know, with my friends.
或者和朋友一起踢球的压力
I feel like I am doing what I like. What I know to do.
我感觉我在做我喜欢的事，我擅长的事
And I try to do it the best I can.
我尽最大努力把它做好
I love the environment,
我喜欢这种环境
the pressure, the fans, the atmosphere.
压力、球迷、氛围
I am passionate about football.
我热爱足球
And I believe that in any job, if you do it with love and really like it,
我相信任何工作，如果你带着热爱去做，真的喜欢它
you enjoy it, no matter how exhausting it is.
不管多累，你都会享受它
It was a childhood dream,
这是儿时的梦想
and that has always motivated me.
这一直激励着我
And it is what continues to motivate me today.
也是现在继续激励我的动力
It's thinking that… it is a,that it is a game,
要想着...这只是一个，这是一场比赛
that it is fun, that you win,
这很有趣，你会赢
you lose, you draw,
可能会输，也可能会平局
any of those three things can happen. And we have to assimilate whatever it comes.
这三种结果都可能发生，我们必须接受任何结果
That way, I try to stay calm.
这样，我试着保持冷静
The game that made me the most nervous was my first professional game.
让我最紧张的比赛是我的第一场职业比赛
When I was younger, I didn't know what to expect.
年轻时，我不知道会发生什么
Or even my first game with Chile.
或者是我为智利队的首秀
A big occasion, many expectations. Also for friends and family.
重要的场合，很多期待，还有朋友和家人的期待
And it is impossible to forget.
这是难以忘记的
It was the 2014 World Cup final
那是2014年世界杯决赛
in which I couldn't play and well… The pressure of whether I could play
我无法上场……压力很大，我是否能上场
or not, if I was injured.If they were going to give me an injection, all of that
我是否受伤了，是否要打针，所有这些
it overwhelmed me too much.
压得我喘不过气来
I cried at night, I cried in the morning.
我晚上哭，早上也哭
The game we had
我们有一场比赛
four or five days after Saudi Arabia, against Mexico.
输给沙特后四五天，对阵墨西哥
And I think it was waking up in the morning and saying "if I lose, I go home".
我想那就是早上醒来说"如果输了，我就要回家了"
I believe in fact that was
我相信事实上那是
the match with the most anxiety and with the most nervousness in my entire career.
我整个职业生涯中最焦虑最紧张的比赛
I think the game I was most nervous about
我觉得我最紧张的比赛
was my World Cup debut.
是我的世界杯首秀
When the coach called me. That was the most anxious moment of my life.
当教练叫我的时候，那是我人生中最焦虑的时刻
My first game when I debuted with the main National Team was ethe one I was most nervous about.
我在国家队的首秀是我最紧张的
Because it was the first time and I played as a starter
因为是第一次，而且我是首发
so it was a bit difficult to assimilate everything.
所以有点难以适应
You get a little nervous, even
你会有点紧张，甚至
when the referee blows the whistle. But only until the initial whistle.
在裁判吹哨的时候，但只是在开场哨响之前
Then, everything becomes normal.
然后，一切就变得正常了
When you are playing with your friends,
当你和朋友一起踢球时
you are not going to lose any championship,
你不会失去任何冠军
you are not going to make it reflect on a whole city or country.
你不会让一整个城市或国家为此感到影响
You are there playing with your friends to have fun.
你只是和朋友一起玩得开心
And on a football field, you have the responsibility to make millions of people happy.
但在足球场上，你有责任让数百万人感到快乐
I think in the big games,
我想在重要比赛中
when you get those butterflies in your tummy,
当你感到紧张的时候
I think it's an amazing feeling.
我觉得那是一种很棒的感觉
When you play as a child, you play for fun, and
小时候踢球，是为了好玩
I remember, we played to see who would pay for the barbecue.
我记得我们踢球是为了决定谁付烧烤的钱
What motivates me the most to strive more and more are probably different scenarios:
最激励我不断努力的可能是不同的场景
When I put on the Chile shirt, for my country, for my family, for my friends.
当我穿上智利球衣，为我的国家、家人、朋友而战
And also when you play at club level it is also for my teammates, and the fans.
在俱乐部层面，也是为了我的队友和球迷
In my mind, before starting the game,
在我的脑海中，在比赛开始前
I feel everything: the emotions,
我感受到一切：那些情感
the desire to play football
踢球的渴望
and of course, it is my passion.
当然，这是我的激情所在
In a warm-up. I remember, in the World Cup,
在热身时，我记得在世界杯上
I can't recall what game it was,
我记不清是哪场比赛了
if quarters or semifinals.
是四分之一决赛还是半决赛
I was warming up,
我在热身
And usually when you play here in England
通常在英格兰比赛时
when you play somewhere else, it's cold…
在其他地方比赛时，天气很冷...
you have to motivate yourself,
你必须激励自己
you have to motivate yourself to defend well.
你必须激励自己防守好
And there, it seemed that the fans were motivating me.
而在那里，感觉球迷在激励我
it was like sweating, and being with the crowd
就像在出汗，和观众在一起
and I felt that I was enjoying the warm-up.
我感觉我在享受热身
I remember when I was a child and played
我记得我小时候踢球时的感觉
I try to do that in the game too.
我也试图在比赛中保持这种感觉
What motivates me are my daughters.
激励我的是我的女儿们
To be able to show them that we can. That, with consistency,
能够向她们展示我们可以做到，通过坚持
that, with effort everything can be achieved. Everything can be overcomed
通过努力一切都能实现，一切都能克服
I followed my father since I was a child, who also played football
从小我就跟随我的父亲，他也踢足球
and with following his footsteps, I found a passion
追随他的脚步，我找到了激情
I am in love with football.
我爱上了足球
Passion
激情
You imagine
你想象着
The things that could happen on the field
可能在球场上发生的事情
and that obviously are constant with what is happening.
这些显然与实际发生的事情是一致的
I think I handled it well, I handled that pressure well,
我想我处理得很好，我很好地处理了那些压力
I handled that moment well.
我很好地处理了那个时刻
I tried minute by minute to handle it in the best way.
我尽力每分钟都以最好的方式应对
Focus on if something went wrong, I could overcome it.
专注于如果有什么事情出错了，我可以克服它
And it was like that.
事实也确实如此
I scored a goal, I remember that match... and I managed to overcome it.
我进了一个球，我记得那场比赛……我成功克服了困难
My best experience was at the World Cup
我最好的经历是在世界杯
and when I went to play against France
当我对阵法国时
those seconds, it was looking at my tammates and everyone was looking back
在那几秒钟里，看着我的队友们，每个人都在看着我
as if they needed me and I
好像他们需要我
stayed calm, do my routine.
而我保持冷静，按照我的节奏来
Focus as much as possible on my work, forgetting the outside, focusing on my teammates.
尽可能专注于我的工作，忘记外界，专注于我的队友
Forget the outside and think only about what we have to do on the field.
忘记外界，只想着我们在场上要做的事
I learned to deal with pressure during the week,
我学会了在一周内应对压力
in every habit, in every meal,
在每个习惯中，在每顿饭中
in every night that I go to bed early.
在每个早睡的夜晚
And I believe in the routine,
我相信日常规律
I think that's how you can handle it well.
我认为这样你就能很好地应对它
Playing in a World Cup
参加世界杯
with billions of people watching, is a totally different pressure,
数十亿人观看，这是完全不同的压力
but the good thing is that we have a group,
但好的是我们有一个团队
that was like playing with Friends and when you play with friends
就像和朋友一起踢球，当你和朋友一起踢球时
it's always… it is fun.
总是...很有趣
Look, I think it is one of the games we were losing recently.
看，我想这是我们最近输掉的一场比赛
3-1 at home.
主场1-3落后
And from the moment we scored a goal, our fans came with everything.
从我们进球的那一刻起，我们的球迷全力支持
They pushed us to turn the situation around, and we managed to turn it around,
他们推动我们扭转局面，我们确实做到了
in the last five minutes. We scored three goals in six minutes.
在最后五分钟，我们在六分钟内打进三球
All games can be won like in life.
所有比赛都可以赢，就像生活一样
If someone wants something and works hard
如果一个人想要什么并且努力工作
and makes many sacrifices to get there
为达到目标做出许多牺牲
everything can be achieved.
一切皆有可能
And those ten seconds I take for myself.
那十秒钟我留给自己
Today I come out victorious. Today I win, today I win, today I win.
今天我要胜利，今天我要赢，今天我要赢，今天我要赢
and I see nothing else but winning.
我眼中只有胜利
And I repeat to myself, I repeat, I repeat until I believe it.
我不断重复，重复，重复直到我相信
Even knowing that it is our job and what feeds us.
即使知道这是我们的工作和生计
I think that becomes secondary,
我认为这变得次要了
when you realize all the moments that you can
当你意识到所有你能够
vivir junto a este deporte.
在这项运动中经历的时刻
For me, in football or in life, I never give up.
对我来说，无论是足球还是生活，我从不放弃
An occasion when pressure pushed me further,
有一次压力推动我更进一步
I think it was in the penalty shootout against…
我想是在对阵洪都拉斯
against Honduras.
点球大战中
I had missed two penalties and
我已经罚丢了两个点球
ended up being the first to kick
最后成为第一个主罚的人
with the Mexican National Team.
在墨西哥国家队
And I knew I had that responsibility to score to advance to the semifinals;
我知道我有那个责任要进球才能晋级半决赛
and also with the pressure of knowing that a whole country depends on you.
而且还有整个国家都依赖你的压力
I think the most important thing is to focus on
我认为最重要的是专注于
practicing the sport and playing what we like the most.
练习这项运动并做我们最喜欢的事情
And since I started playing
从我开始踢球起
I always faced it that way, in having fun, in enjoying.
我总是这样面对它，享受乐趣
Of course, at times there is more pressure than others
当然，有时压力会比其他时候大
and the reality is different,
现实也是不同的
but in the end
但最终
it is a game you want to enjoy and have fun with.
这是一场你想要享受和获得乐趣的比赛
I learned a lot to deal with pressure
我学会了很多应对压力的方法
in conversations, in several conversations with my family,
通过交谈，通过与家人的多次交谈
who are football, people who played,
尤其是那些踢过球的足球界人士
who were on the field and knew what it meant,
他们在球场上知道这意味着什么
so they were always there to teach me
所以他们一直在那里教导我
how to overcome all This and how to
如何克服这一切以及如何
make it just a driving force.
把它变成一种动力
What motivates me to strive more
激励我不断努力的是
and more is to fulfill my dreams,
实现我的梦想
also because I know that my family
也因为我知道我的家人
is proud of me.
为我感到骄傲
My children and my family.
我的孩子和我的家人
All my life I fought for my family
我一生都在为我的家人而战
when it was in Mar del Plata and today I do it for my children.
在马德普拉塔时是这样，今天我为我的孩子们这样做
For my family. To deal with the pressure.
为了我的家人，为了应对压力
Living a normal life, makes you get out a little of what this pressure is
过正常的生活，让你能稍微摆脱这种压力
that you can feel and for me it is fundamental.
你能感受到的压力，对我来说这是根本
I use it as… I don't know how to explain it to you…
我把它用作...我不知道该如何向你解释...
when you have a good car and put the best gasoline in it.
就像你有一辆好车，给它加最好的汽油
I feel that the people of Argentina gives me that gasoline
我感觉阿根廷人民给了我那种汽油
I need to start the game.
是我开始比赛所需要的
Football
足球
I play football because it is what I am passionate about,
我踢足球是因为这是我的激情所在
It is what I have always liked, since I was little
这是我从小就一直喜欢的
I play football because it is what I have always done when I was younger
我踢足球是因为这是我年轻时一直在做的事情
I love playing football.
我热爱踢足球
I play football because I like it, because I enjoy it a lot,
我踢足球是因为我喜欢，因为我非常享受
because I come from a family that taught me what it means.
因为我来自一个向我传递了其中意义的家庭
Because since I was a child I followed my father.
因为从小我就跟随我的父亲
I have always dreamed of being a professional player.
我一直梦想成为一名职业球员
I always dreamed of playing in a big club.
我一直梦想在大俱乐部踢球
I play football because it has always been my dream
我踢足球是因为这一直是我的梦想
It's my passion, my life.
这是我的激情，我的生活
It's the only thing I know to do, and that's why I play football.
这是我唯一会做的事，这就是我踢足球的原因
Out of love.
因为热爱
I love football.
我爱足球
I love my profesión I love diving, I love getting hurt…
我爱我的职业，我爱扑救，我爱受伤...
Because I love football, because it makes me happy to play football
因为我爱足球，因为踢球让我快乐
I feel it makes me happy. Makes my family happy.
我感觉这让我快乐，让我的家人快乐
And I try to make the children happy too, the number of children
我也试图让孩子们快乐，那些关注我们的孩子
who follow us and try to show that everything is possible.
试图向他们展示一切皆有可能